KANWAR ANAND

225 Cedarbrae Ave. Waterloo, ON | 519-501-0499

kanwar.b.anand@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/kanand2

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

PERFORMANCE | INTEGRITY | LEADERSHIP

I am a customer-focused product manager committed to making sure technology and products help users achieve what they need. I lead teams dedicated to working closely with customers and driving the optimal user experience through diverse channels. I strike a balance between customer wants and business needs, and work with product teams to implement solutions that help users get the most out of our tools and services, and hopefully love doing it.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DIGITAL ASSOCIATE PRODUCT MANAGER

MANULIFE | 2015 - CURRENT

- ➤ Manage digital products including web collateral and mobile apps from inception to launch.
- > Develop user stories, personas, wireframes, roadmaps, test plans, marketing material, KPIs and more.
- Run usability sessions and channel feedback into changes via rapid prototyping.
- ➤ Provide leadership, training material and expert advice to team members and influence stakeholders.
- Present digital capabilities and vision at sales finalist presentations and client visits.

USER ENGAGEMENT PROGRAM LEAD

BLACKBERRY | 2013 - 2015

- ➤ Managed digital strategy and user engagement best practices for beta programs that touch 5,000+ internal customers and upwards of 40,000 external monthly active users.
- Managed and lead a team of 8 project managers running technical and customer facing projects.
- ➤ Developed digital analytics to assess product performance and trends in customer sentiment.
- ➤ SME for Voice of the Customer programs and main contact for multi-level stakeholders.
- Prioritized and tracked defects to closure and identified usability concerns.

USER ENGAGEMENT PROJECT SPECIALIST

BLACKBERRY | 2010 - 2013

- Managed large projects throughout their life cycles using Agile methodologies in a matrix environment.
- Provided thought leadership on feedback analysis and defined best practices for user engagement.
- Prepared project documentation and streamlined stakeholder reporting.

TECHNICAL CUSTOMER SUPPORT LEAD

BLACKBERRY | 2008 - 2009

- ➤ Supported pre-release BlackBerry products in the global contact centre.
- ➤ Managed technological solutions and process refinement to continually improve the customer experience.
- ➤ Provided top tier service to internal and external customers for high profile products.

EDUCATION

MASTERS OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION (CANDIDATE)

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING SCIENCE, ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE

LAURIER UNIVERSITY | 2018

Western University | 2010 Western University | 2010

KEY SKILLS & QUALIFICATIONS

PRODUCT MANAGEMENT - Manage product stories and defects, tracking in-scope items to completion over iterative releases. Track KPIs (like NPS) to drive customer-focused refinements into latest products.

PROJECT MANAGEMENT - Manage and run large-scale, fast-paced programs, and work with department leads to carry out actionable solutions on time and budget.

CUSTOMER ENGAGEMENT - Organize, moderate and support customer engagement sessions using presentations, online forums and surveys, webinars, live focus groups and testing sessions.

KPI TRACKING - Increased customer satisfaction quality targets from 56% to 77% by driving critical issues to closure and working with Product teams to refine customer facing concerns.

DEFECT TRACKING & PRIORITIZATION – Raised the average defect fix rate from 70% to 90%+ for each release by working closer with senior management and coordinating product development focus.

RELATIONSHIP MANAGEMENT - Cultivate and maintain positive relationships with users, Senior Management, Product Management, Dev Leads, QA Leads, Customer Support Organizations, Marketing Directors and more.

THOUGHT LEADERSHIP – Coach and lead team members to innovate program management best practices and influence product release planning across the organization at many different accountability levels.

DATA ANALYSIS – Create front-end dashboards to aggregate testing data into meaningful visual representations that provide a big-picture view of product health and identify opportunities for growth and improvements.

TEST PLAN CREATION & STRATEGY - Supervise creation and execution of user testing plans for complex, fast-paced product validation programs using innovative best fit test models.

PROCESS MANAGEMENT - Optimize existing processes and manage waste reduction using Lean methodology.

SYSTEMS ANALYSIS - Maintain an understanding of technical systems architecture, and verify capabilities to support new products and services that meet business objectives and user needs.

RELEASE MANAGEMENT - Work with cross-functional department leads and project managers to prioritize features, evolve testing focus and ensure release timeframes are on track.

REPORTING - Design concise and comprehensive reports for executive stakeholders.

TOOLS EXPERTISE - Experienced with industry tools including

- Advanced Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Visio)
- Online user engagement & content management (Beta Zone, Survey Monkey, Livelink, Igloo, custom tools)
- > HTML, SQL & PHP fundamentals
- Web & Mobile app design (Dreamweaver, Notepad++, Android SDK)

COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS

- Project Management Fundaments
- Virtual Workplace Effectiveness
- Scrum Fundamentals

- ➤ Six Sigma Green Belt
- ➤ Active Leadership
- **▶** Gamification

- > 7 Habits of Highly Effective People
- Innovation for Entrepreneurs: From Idea to Marketplace